<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-07-17T19:32:04+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">AVL</title><subtitle>A front-end developer with over two years experience in building well designed, beautiful and forward-thinking websites.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Jekyll!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2018/04/27/welcome-to-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Jekyll!" /><published>2018-04-27T11:14:28+01:00</published><updated>2018-04-27T11:14:28+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2018/04/27/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2018/04/27/welcome-to-jekyll.html">&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext&lt;/code&gt; and includes the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'Tom'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints 'Hi, Tom' to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/home&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://talk.jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">You’ll find this post in your _posts directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run jekyll serve, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">E-DICTION</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/03/15/ediction.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="E-DICTION" /><published>2018-03-15T10:14:28+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-15T10:14:28+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/03/15/ediction</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/03/15/ediction.html">&lt;p&gt;How long have you ever gone without using any personal (or work) digital device? Or maybe more importantly, how far do you think you could go without any? Maslow’s hierarchy of needs is a motivational theory in psychology comprised of a five-tier ‘human necessity’ pyramid. To explain a little deeper if unfamiliar, and note I am not a psychologist but rather a humble developer, Maslow decided that people are driven to achieve certain needs and that some of those were more important than others; hence the pyramid structure. The requirements are essentially primal and survival.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Has technology become such a motivating factor for people in and of itself, or do we simply use technology and gadgets to just make us happy?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once bottom and thus most important level of the pyramid is fulfilled, people are motivated by the next level up, and so forth until they reach the top. So the question is can technology ever become part of this hierarchy? Has technology become such a motivating factor for people in and of itself, or do we simply use technology and gadgets to just make us happy? Obviously, the first level of the so-called ‘Basic Needs’ are inherently physically, we cannot eat technology to not starve. At least, not directly… Where we do not use it for that purpose, it has revolutionised agriculture and all forms of food production. So, should it disappear, could we as a race survive effectively?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, on a direct one to one impact, is technology fulfilling the rest of our needs for us? With the internet becoming a place where many work, socialise and almost live in, it is arguable that a proportion of the population don’t need the real world to fulfil many levels of their needs. Think about the little rush of when your Instagram photo gets an abundance of likes or your Facebook post sparks a conversation. Sharing on social media helps people feel useful, interesting and wanted, no matter how fleeting and superficially. Consider how it allows long-distance friends, family members and lovers to stay in touch; to not feel alone or separated even through hundreds of thousands of miles. In a direct sense, technology can fulfil the ‘Social Needs’ relating to the feeling of belonging to something and a sense of love, without which mental disorders could be wider spread and harder to overcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This, therefore, could transcend a direct relationship of tech to the user, and I’d go so far as to say past the ‘Basic Needs’. Technology can now facilitate every level of needs modern people, to the extent that some generations are becoming raised largely detached from simple knowledge and activities – reliant on their personal digital device to essentially guide them through life. With the true advent of virtual reality finally at our fingertips, the Sci-fi idea of living within a virtual world which makes us feel better than the real one is no longer such a laughable idea; technology already can make us happier than things in the real world, and even when the real world comes close we are so in awe that we often have a burning desire to capture it digitally somehow. So, is a true virtual future so far away, and is it something we as a species have become so reliant on that it has earned a plinth alongside survival necessities?
However, on a direct one to one impact, is technology fulfilling the rest of our needs for us? With the internet becoming a place where many work, socialise, and almost live in, it is arguable that a proportion of the population don’t need the real world to fulfil many levels of their needs. Think about the little rush of when your Instagram photo gets an abundance of likes or your Facebook post sparks a conversation. Sharing on social media helps people feel useful, interesting and wanted, no matter how fleeting and superficially. Consider how it allows long distance friends, family members and lovers to stay in touch; to not feel alone or separated even through hundreds of thousands of miles. In a direct sense, technology can fulfil the ‘Social Needs’ relating to the feeling of belonging to something and a sense of love, without which mental disorders could be wider spread and harder to overcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This therefore could transcend a direct relationship of tech to user, and I’d go so far as to say past the ‘Basic Needs’. Technology can now facilitate every level of needs modern people, to the extent that some generations are becoming raised largely detached from simple knowledge and activities – reliant on their personal digital device to essentially guide them through live. With the true advent of virtual reality finally at our fingertips, the Sci-fi idea of living within a virtual world which makes us feel better than the real one is no longer such a laughable idea; technology already can make us happier than things in the real world, and even when the real world comes close we are so in awe that we often have a burning desire to capture it digitally somehow. So, is a true virtual future so far away, and is it something we as a species have become so reliant on that it has earned a plinth alongside survival necessities?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">How long have you ever gone without using any personal (or work) digital device? Or maybe more importantly, how far do you think you could go without any? Maslow’s hierarchy of needs is a motivational theory in psychology comprised of a five-tier ‘human necessity’ pyramid. To explain a little deeper if unfamiliar, and note I am not a psychologist but rather a humble developer, Maslow decided that people are driven to achieve certain needs and that some of those were more important than others; hence the pyramid structure. The requirements are essentially primal and survival.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Uncharted: The Lost Legacy</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/games2018/2018/02/16/uncharted.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Uncharted: The Lost Legacy" /><published>2018-02-16T10:14:28+00:00</published><updated>2018-02-16T10:14:28+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/games2018/2018/02/16/uncharted</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/games2018/2018/02/16/uncharted.html">&lt;p&gt;The most refreshing thing about Uncharted: Lost Legacy is not the new gameplay twists or exciting locales. But the well written, funny and touching between two women, one who is mixed race and one who is Black South African. It is rare, in any media, to see a story like this but in games, this might be a first. Lost Legacy shows that Uncharted loses nothing by dropping Nathan Drake, it still has all the fun, drama and fizzle the series is known for but is finally telling a worthwhile tale as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You play as Chloe Frazer, a swashbuckling treasure hunter in the mould of Nathan Drake. Chloe is every bit as charming and sarcastic as Nathan Drake but helped immensely by the fact she’s a mixed-race, Australian woman and not a straight white man. Voiced by Claudia Black, she delivers a performance like no other, with a charm and warmth that feels as if you’ve known her for years but with a subtle edge that hints at the sad past that drives her. Naughty Dog created a better Nathan Drake and it works very well. Chloe’s foil through her adventure is Nadine Ross, her opposite in every way except their ability to kill men without blinking. Nadine is stern, tough and straight to the point, and it’s refreshing to see Naughty Dog write someone who isn’t constantly quipping and dripping with sarcasm. Immediately they don’t blend well as a duo but their growing warmth and friendship throughout the game are done beautifully. They start as strangers but end up as friends, having so many cute exchanges you’ll want a friendship like theirs by the end of the game. The pair’s developing friendship is the driving force for the story as the actual plot is fairly lacklustre. Chloe and Nadine are on the hunt for another long lost treasure because they need money and father-daughter closure (very Lara Croft). Along the way, they encounter a warlord who is bad, and that is all there is to him. Thankfully there is no mysticism involved, it is a simple treasure hunt story which allows the interpersonal relationships to take centre stage. And Lost Legacy is all the better for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gameplay wise you can clearly tell that this was once planned to be a simple piece of DLC for Uncharted 4. Naughty Dog took very few risks with it simply expanding on the new ideas they introduced in 4. The large-ish areas return, feeling more fleshed out this time. In Lost Legacy, these roam-able areas actually have side activities and changing patterns to help breath life into them. The driving is still more fun than you would think and platforming is as Uncharted as it ever was but the less the said about the shooting the better. Once again all I can say is that the gunplay works and it’s fine but I wish was better but hey it works. What is more disappointing to me is that I hoped they would have given you more tools to explore stealth options. This still remains the best thing they introduced in Uncharted 4 and feels much truer to how these characters would really act when up against these odds. Luckily for Naughty Dog, the gameplay is mindless and fun enough to make sure it doesn’t get in the way. Come to Lost Legacy to witness Chloe and Nadine’s story and enjoy the gameplay as much as you can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The general consensus around the internet is that one of Lost Legacy’s strengths is its relative brevity compared to Uncharted 4. On the one hand, I agree, Lost Legacy shows what a good editor can do, as it sums up and combines all the best elements of the series. Without the weight and baggage, the series had developed. Yet I’m torn, the strength of the writing for both Chloe and Nadine and the strength Naughty Dog has shown writing characters out of the typical straight, white, male trope, has me wishing there was more. If only we had a world in which we’d received four full length, triple-A budget games about two female action heroes. Two women who are simply good at what they do and don’t follow the usual plot tropes we so sadly expect. But as that world doesn’t yet exist, Lost Legacy will do just fine in the meantime. I’m glad to see large companies like Sony and Naughty Dog taking the chance to see that yes, there are other viewpoints and characters out there to be told. And they can be better than what we’ve become so used to. Lost Legacy is a great game and a truly excellent end for the series, doing something new and doing it extremely well.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The most refreshing thing about Uncharted: Lost Legacy is not the new gameplay twists or exciting locales. But the well written, funny and touching between two women, one who is mixed race and one who is Black South African. It is rare, in any media, to see a story like this but in games, this might be a first. Lost Legacy shows that Uncharted loses nothing by dropping Nathan Drake, it still has all the fun, drama and fizzle the series is known for but is finally telling a worthwhile tale as well.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Splatoon 2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/games2018/2018/02/01/splatoon.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Splatoon 2" /><published>2018-02-01T10:14:28+00:00</published><updated>2018-02-01T10:14:28+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/games2018/2018/02/01/splatoon</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/games2018/2018/02/01/splatoon.html">&lt;p&gt;So yes, the first thing on this year’s list was also on last years list, but that’s just how good Splatoon 2 is! There is no better game from this year or last, to spend anything from 15 minutes or 3 hours with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Splatoon 2 simply feels great, everything from the shooting to swimming through ink has that Nintendo touch of quality. And don’t get me started on the style, it is still as fresh as when it first came out. The graphic design, the squid looks and the weird fish-rock music. This is the world that I want to die in. Nintendo has also done a great job updating Splatoon and managing to keep the community engaged, pushing out new content and game fixes regularly. Splatoon 2 has been allowed to grow and thrive and is still as fun to jump into today as it was in August.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is what I said about Splatoon 2 last year:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Looking back, the idea that Nintendo couldn’t make an amazing shooter seems absurd. They’ve managed to conquer every other genre, so why would a competitive shooter be the one Nintendo would disappoint on.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yet that’s exactly what I and many other people thought when hearing about the first Splatoon when it was announced. But Nintendo did what Nintendo does best, proving everyone wrong. And Splatoon 2 is the perfect execution of Nintendo’s competitive shooter vision.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A bright, colourful and just damn cool world. Splatoon is 90s attitude through bright Japanese neon with a side helping of charm. The basic premise is that four teams of squid kids battle it out, not to kill one another, but to paint as much of the map as possible. This simple twist on the genre makes a game that feels like nothing else on the market.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Matches are very quick, limited to 3 minutes only. Which at first seems annoying but slowly you realise how much of a masterstroke this is. If you’re losing badly, it’s over quickly then you’re back in another match and if you’re winning it doesn’t last long enough so you need another match to keep that euphoric feeling going. It creates the perfect ‘just one more game feeling’ and then out of nowhere you realise you’ve been playing for hours. Sure there are plenty of weird Nintendo decisions, like limiting weapon changes and the fact the excellent horde mode is only available at certain times (no seriously, this decision is insane?!).
But nothing can change the fact that Splatoon is just joyous fun and a masterclass of the genre. It has so much charm and is so fun you’ll quickly forget that Splatoon wasn’t always part of Nintendo’s pantheon of games.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">So yes, the first thing on this year’s list was also on last years list, but that’s just how good Splatoon 2 is! There is no better game from this year or last, to spend anything from 15 minutes or 3 hours with.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Online Privacy</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/01/20/onlineprivacy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Online Privacy" /><published>2018-01-20T10:14:28+00:00</published><updated>2018-01-20T10:14:28+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/01/20/onlineprivacy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/01/20/onlineprivacy.html">&lt;p&gt;Privacy is the hot topic in the tech world over the past year and something I’ve been thinking about recently. With high profile cases such as Apple’s fight against the American Government in refusal to allow unfettered access to iOS. Some companies are finally taking a stand against many Government’s lack of respect for online privacy. Along with myself, I feel that the general public is now more aware of the scale of data being collected about each and every one of us. To anyone who says privacy fears are unwanted paranoia, I have a simple task for you. Go to Google Maps, signed in with your own google account and look at your ‘Your Timeline’. Take a second to look around and see what this really is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smart phones are one thing and can be set down and disconnected from. But technology is quickly becoming integrated into every part of our live’s
Your smart phone, in conjunction with Google Maps is creating a record of everywhere you have gone and will go while carrying your phone, through gps tracking and cell tower location. This isn’t just weird but can and has been used by various governments around the world to prosecute people, as it is accurate enough to pinpoint your location exactly. (http://www.theverge.com/2016/6/1/11824118/google-android-location-data-police-warrants).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smart phones are one thing and can be set down and disconnected from. But technology is quickly becoming integrated into every part of our live’s. Watches, which once simply told the time, are now computers. Computers can collect even more personal information than our smartphones. Smart watches and general wearables like Fitbits have more data on your personal health than some people’s doctors. Will your insurance be tied to how healthy you actually are? Already insurance companies are trailing this, such as Vitality in the UK. Almost like a science-fiction novel come to life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do we really want all this information logged on a server somewhere? Do we really trust large corporations and our own government to use this data ethically?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Privacy is the hot topic in the tech world over the past year and something I’ve been thinking about recently. With high profile cases such as Apple’s fight against the American Government in refusal to allow unfettered access to iOS. Some companies are finally taking a stand against many Government’s lack of respect for online privacy. Along with myself, I feel that the general public is now more aware of the scale of data being collected about each and every one of us. To anyone who says privacy fears are unwanted paranoia, I have a simple task for you. Go to Google Maps, signed in with your own google account and look at your ‘Your Timeline’. Take a second to look around and see what this really is.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Wolfenstein II The New Colossus</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/games2017/2017/12/19/wolfenstein.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wolfenstein II The New Colossus" /><published>2017-12-19T10:14:28+00:00</published><updated>2017-12-19T10:14:28+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/games2017/2017/12/19/wolfenstein</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/games2017/2017/12/19/wolfenstein.html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The story is batshit crazy, in the best possible way.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I won’t spoil it but my god, Machine Games goes to some crazy places that you never will see coming.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yet every character is superbly written and well rounded.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The human drama element, is better than most of games. And better than games are expected to be.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Grace, the leader of the American resistance, is possibly the best written character in a video game in a long while.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Also shoutout to Sigrun, who is amazing. Her ‘I’m not a NAZI’ scene was perfect and had me cheering!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;But one of the best scenes goes to when you meet Horton for the first time. It is masterfully cinematic in the way it is shot and use of music throughout. No game has come close to that before. The way the tension rises, yet how it clashes with the absurdity of the scene in a way that just works.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;BJ’s monologues give him so much more depth than most player characters. He is an inhuman tank yet his emotions and desires feel very grounded and real.  The whole level set on his childhood home paints a picture of person so deeply scarred by their past and with such desire for revenge. Yet that revenge brings him no solace except the fact that it has been done.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The actual gameplay is good but could be so much better.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The guns lack any real oomph and the lack of feedback when you’re getting shot makes it impossible to accurately know how close to death you are. It is far too easy being shot and yet have no idea. Which results in a quick death and lots of frustration. Many deaths that you could have avoided if the feedback about your health was better handled.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The stealth is, at times, fun and satisfying but again lacks proper feedback and visual alerts. With no map or alert states for enemies, it is far too easy to be spotted and have no clue how that happened or how you could have prevented it. At its worst you feel like you’re bumbling around.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The constant respawning enemies until you take out the commanders gets old, fast. It reduces these areas to one boring tactic, run past every enemy as fast as you can until you get to the commander and kill him. No room for any other strategy or style.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unlike last years Doom, which this feels like it is trying to match. The combat encounters rarely change and how you approach combat scenarios matters very little. They all devolve into the same rinse and repeat style.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If only this played like Doom, sigh.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Then it would be a 10/10, console generational classic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;But it is still an unmissable game, with one of the best and well-told stories in video gaming. Seriously, don’t let the minor gameplay annoyances put you off. Just play this game! You owe it to yourself to experience it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And it is the perfect game for 2017.  It stunningly and expertly shows you why Nazi’s are the actual worst, why they are still awful, even in the future and why we should kill them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The story is batshit crazy, in the best possible way. I won’t spoil it but my god, Machine Games goes to some crazy places that you never will see coming. Yet every character is superbly written and well rounded. The human drama element, is better than most of games. And better than games are expected to be. Grace, the leader of the American resistance, is possibly the best written character in a video game in a long while. Also shoutout to Sigrun, who is amazing. Her ‘I’m not a NAZI’ scene was perfect and had me cheering! But one of the best scenes goes to when you meet Horton for the first time. It is masterfully cinematic in the way it is shot and use of music throughout. No game has come close to that before. The way the tension rises, yet how it clashes with the absurdity of the scene in a way that just works. BJ’s monologues give him so much more depth than most player characters. He is an inhuman tank yet his emotions and desires feel very grounded and real. The whole level set on his childhood home paints a picture of person so deeply scarred by their past and with such desire for revenge. Yet that revenge brings him no solace except the fact that it has been done. The actual gameplay is good but could be so much better. The guns lack any real oomph and the lack of feedback when you’re getting shot makes it impossible to accurately know how close to death you are. It is far too easy being shot and yet have no idea. Which results in a quick death and lots of frustration. Many deaths that you could have avoided if the feedback about your health was better handled. The stealth is, at times, fun and satisfying but again lacks proper feedback and visual alerts. With no map or alert states for enemies, it is far too easy to be spotted and have no clue how that happened or how you could have prevented it. At its worst you feel like you’re bumbling around. The constant respawning enemies until you take out the commanders gets old, fast. It reduces these areas to one boring tactic, run past every enemy as fast as you can until you get to the commander and kill him. No room for any other strategy or style. Unlike last years Doom, which this feels like it is trying to match. The combat encounters rarely change and how you approach combat scenarios matters very little. They all devolve into the same rinse and repeat style. If only this played like Doom, sigh. Then it would be a 10/10, console generational classic But it is still an unmissable game, with one of the best and well-told stories in video gaming. Seriously, don’t let the minor gameplay annoyances put you off. Just play this game! You owe it to yourself to experience it. And it is the perfect game for 2017. It stunningly and expertly shows you why Nazi’s are the actual worst, why they are still awful, even in the future and why we should kill them.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Super Mario Odyssey</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/games2017/2017/11/07/supermario.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Super Mario Odyssey" /><published>2017-11-07T10:14:28+00:00</published><updated>2017-11-07T10:14:28+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/games2017/2017/11/07/supermario</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/games2017/2017/11/07/supermario.html">&lt;p&gt;Man, Nintendo is on a roll, a serious roll. Zelda, Mario Kart, Splatoon and now this, the best Mario game in years. 2017 is the year of Nintendo. And Super Mario Odyssey is the photo finish to prove it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If Breath of the Wild was a drastic rebirth for its series, then Odyssey is a beautiful return to form. A return to the wondrous toy boxes of Mario 64 and Sunshine (I enjoyed it ok. It’s fine to like it), after the more controlled and streamlined Wii and Wii U entries. Each world in Odyssey is filled with weird and wonderful things to do, all in the search for Moons. These moons are much much more plentiful than Mario 64’s stars and around every corner there is a to get one, hidden behind a simple platforming challenge or by helping a distressed denizen of the world. It’s this change that makes Odyssey feel so creative, as your time and experimentation is always rewarded. Nintendo has filled these world’s to the brim things to do, ranging from very simple to true Mario platforming challenges. At times it feels like there a moons placed every two seconds in the worlds but luckily nearly all of them are fun to get.
Never-mind that this is the weirdest Mario game Nintendo has ever created. There’s a New York-inspired city that’s filled with humans who don’t look like Mario?! A world filled with sentient forks who are expert cooks, with a visual style that Nintendo HAS to use in a full game. I haven’t seen something that’s so inspired me in a long time. And not to mention the game features one of the coolest video game dogs ever, best character of the year in my book.
Odyssey feels like Nintendo’s designers were allowed to be as creative as possible, nothing was too weird or too out there and it makes for a game that is just joyous to play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All this focus on weird and wonderful worlds hasn’t meant that Nintendo dropped the ball when it comes to the gameplay. Mario runs and jumps as smooth and satisfying as always, with some new additions that change up the formula. The biggest addition is Cappy, Mario’s iconic red cap is now a living being that he can use to ‘capture’ other creatures and take control of them. Yes, this feature is as bizarre as it sounds, and the cutscene that plays the first time is an existential nightmare. But let’s ignore that and focus on how cool it is to control a goomba, complete with a Mario hat and moustache! The range of things you can control is as fun and creative as the rest of the game. And truly gives the game a distinct feeling that sets it apart from its 3D predecessors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nintendo has also changed the Mario formula in the length and the structure of the game. Unlike previous games, you can breeze through the main game with relative ease. This works in the game’s favour as it allows the harder challenges to be hidden, adding an extra layer of reward. And if the game really is truly easy for you, please just wait until you beat the story once. Every world adds brand new challenges and entire new worlds become objectives to unlock. With Nintendo using these post-game areas to create some of the most fiendishly challenging Mario levels ever devised. Trust me, you will no longer have the feeling Odyssey is too easy once you hit these areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Mario Odyssey, Nintendo has managed to deliver one of the best Mario and video games in years. Creating a vibrant and beautiful world filled with mechanically excellent things to do. It seems to be very fitting that one of the best years in Nintendo’s existence, is closed out with one of the best Mario games. The favourite child done good.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Man, Nintendo is on a roll, a serious roll. Zelda, Mario Kart, Splatoon and now this, the best Mario game in years. 2017 is the year of Nintendo. And Super Mario Odyssey is the photo finish to prove it.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Wind Up Bird Chronicle</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/books/2017/11/05/windup.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Wind Up Bird Chronicle" /><published>2017-11-05T10:14:28+00:00</published><updated>2017-11-05T10:14:28+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/books/2017/11/05/windup</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/books/2017/11/05/windup.html">&lt;p&gt;The Wind Up Bird Chronicle might be as complex a novel as Murakami has ever done. A simple story of a disintegrating marriage starts Toru Okada on a journey which sees him slowly pulled into an otherworldly place laying below the surface of Tokyo. Nothing is what is seems in this novel but Murkami guides you through which such heart, emotion and humour you can’t help but fall in as deep as the protagonist.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Haruki Murakami</name></author><summary type="html">The Wind Up Bird Chronicle might be as complex a novel as Murakami has ever done. A simple story of a disintegrating marriage starts Toru Okada on a journey which sees him slowly pulled into an otherworldly place laying below the surface of Tokyo. Nothing is what is seems in this novel but Murkami guides you through which such heart, emotion and humour you can’t help but fall in as deep as the protagonist.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Under the Skin</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/books/2017/11/05/undertheskin.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Under the Skin" /><published>2017-11-05T10:14:28+00:00</published><updated>2017-11-05T10:14:28+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/books/2017/11/05/undertheskin</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/books/2017/11/05/undertheskin.html">&lt;p&gt;Having come to this after seeing the film, the novel is a completely different beast. Altogether much darker and much funnier, Under the Skin is a great tale of an alien view looking in on humanity and all it’s flaws. Featuring an alien who must kidnap men, it is through these men that her own notions of humanity and compassion are challenged. A fascinating journey of a book that is nothing like you will expect. A definite must read.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Michel Faber</name></author><summary type="html">Having come to this after seeing the film, the novel is a completely different beast. Altogether much darker and much funnier, Under the Skin is a great tale of an alien view looking in on humanity and all it’s flaws. Featuring an alien who must kidnap men, it is through these men that her own notions of humanity and compassion are challenged. A fascinating journey of a book that is nothing like you will expect. A definite must read.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Grace of Kings</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/books/2017/11/05/grace.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Grace of Kings" /><published>2017-11-05T10:14:28+00:00</published><updated>2017-11-05T10:14:28+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/books/2017/11/05/grace</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/books/2017/11/05/grace.html">&lt;p&gt;The Grace of Kings is an epic fantasy through the eyes of a Chinese author. This brings really interesting twists to old fantasy tropes, unbridled with how things are meant to be done that so many authors are stuck on. World building like Toliken but a world that follows different rules than you would expect. Overall an excellent fantasy read.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ken Liu</name></author><summary type="html">The Grace of Kings is an epic fantasy through the eyes of a Chinese author. This brings really interesting twists to old fantasy tropes, unbridled with how things are meant to be done that so many authors are stuck on. World building like Toliken but a world that follows different rules than you would expect. Overall an excellent fantasy read.</summary></entry></feed>